A Guide to the Grayson County (Va.) Tax and Fiscal Records, 1852-1973 (bulk 1852-1935)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Grayson County (Va.) Tax and Fiscal Records, 1852-1973 (bulk 1852-1935)
The Library of Virginia
1046901-1150641 circa
51 boxes and or volumes.
Grayson County (Va.) Circuit Court
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in a shipment of court papers from Grayson County.
Historical Information
Grayson County was named for William Grayson, a delegate to the Continental Congress from 1784 to 1787 and one of the first two United States senators from Virginia. It was formed from Wythe County in 1792, and a part of Patrick County was added in 1810.
Scope and Content
Grayson County (Va.) Tax and Fiscal Records, 1852-1965 (bulk 1852-1935) contains Land Tax Books 1852-1935, Poll Tax List 1936-1965, copies of Reassessments, 1875-1915 (taken every five years), Personal Property Tax Books for 1872, 1874, 1877, and 1879, Delinquent Land Tax Books 1884-1913 (bulk 1892-1898), County Court Clerk's Tax Book, 1898-1905, and audit reports.
Audit reports include calendar year reports for the clerk and fiscal year reports for the county. Reports between 1941-1950 were conducted by private CPAs. Reports between 1951-1973 were conducted by Auditor of Public Accounts. Also included are specific fiscal year audit reports for the following: Judge of Juvenile and Domestic Relations, 1958-1966, Trial Justice and County Court Judges, 1951-1957, Textbook Fund of the School Board, 1953, and Sheriff, 1960.
Road Warrants, 1899-1927, were retained due to their pre-1913 content. Books for districts of Elk Creek, Old Town, and Wilson. These books document date of presentation, date of warrant, amount, number, in whose favor drawn, and date of payment.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional Grayson County Court Records can be found on microfilm at the Library of Virginia. Consult "A Guide to Virginia County and City Records on Microfilm"
For detached pages from various land tax books and personal property tax books that may be referenced in this collection at the Library of Virginia, consult "A Guide to the Grayson County (VA.) Tax and Fiscal Records, Loose Papers, 1830 circa-1937 (bulk 1858-1937)"
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Grayson County (Va.) Circuit Court
Subjects:
Public Records--Virginia--Grayson County
Geographical Names:
Grayson County (Va.)--History
Genre and Form Terms:
Local government records--Virginia--Grayson County
Contents List
- Land Tax Books, 1852-1935, Extent: 36 volumes
- Land Tax Book, 1852-1859
- Land Tax Book, 1860-1862, 1865
- Land Tax Book, 1866-1870
- Land Tax Book, 1871-1873
- Land Tax Book, 1874-1876
- Land Tax Book, 1877-1878
- Land Tax Book, 1879-1880
- Land Tax Book, 1881-1882
- Land Tax Book, 1883-1884
- Land Tax Book, 1884-1885
- Land Tax Book, 1886-1887
- Land Tax Book, 1888-1889
- Land Tax Book, 1890-1892
- Land Tax Book, 1893-1896
- Land Tax Book, 1897-1899
- Land Tax Book, 1900-1902
- Land Tax Book, 1903-1904
- Land Tax Book, 1905
- Land Tax Book, 1906-1907
- Land Tax Book, 1908-1909
- Land Tax Book, 1910
- Land Tax Book, 1911
- Land Tax Book, 1912
- Land Tax Book, 1913
- Land Tax Book, 1914
- Land Tax Book, 1915
- Land Tax Book, 1916-1917
- Land Tax Book, 1918
- Land Tax Book, 1919, 1921
- Land Tax Book, 1920
- Land Tax Book, 1922-1923
- Land Tax Book, 1924-1925
- Land Tax Book, 1926-1927
- Land Tax Book, 1928-1929
- Land Tax Book, 1930, 1932-1933
- Land Tax Book, 1934-1935
- Other Material
- Poll Tax Lists, (broken series) 1936-1965
- Reassessments, 1875-1890
- Reassessments, 1900, 1905
- Reassessments, 1910, 1915
- Personal Property Tax Books, 1872, 1874, 1877, 1879
- Delinquent Land Tax Book, 1884-1889
- Delinquent Land Tax Book, 1892-1898
- Delinquent Land Tax Book, 1895-1898, 1912-1913
- County Court Tax Book, 1898-1905
- County and Clerk's Audit Reports, 1941-1959
- County and Clerk's Audit Reports; Trial Justices and County Court Judge Audit Reports, etc. 1960-1967, 1951-1966
- County and Clerk's Audit Reports, 1951-1973
- Road Warrants, Elk Creek District, 1899-1927
- Road Warrants, Old Town District, 1899-1927
- Road Warrants, Wilson District, 1899-1927